Nicolas Langlois . Jarvis Consulting

I've always been intrigued by electronics, so as a curious and creative person it's no surprise that I jumped into software engineering. I graduated a few years back at CDI College and obtained an ACS. I have about 5 years of experience, mainly in the game industry as a developer with two of my most-used tools being C# and SQL. I am looking forward to growing in a data role or a back end role.

Skills

Proficient: C#, RDBMS/SQL, MongoDB, Unity, Git

Competent: Microsoft Azure Cosmos DB, PHP, Agile, Python, Node.js

Familiar: C++, websocket, rest API, Java, Linux

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_demo

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Implemented a SQL database to store hardware and usage data on a Linux cluster. The database was created using PostgreSQL inside of a Docker container and gathers the data of various machines with a bash script that runs once at the start and one that runs every 5 minutes.

Highlighted Projects

Hospital Patient Manager: Created a C# application to manage room availability, patient files and worker files. Using an Access database connected to the app through ERP, the app manages a whole hospital system to assign patients rooms, nurses and keep track of a lot of data regarding everything that happens in the hospital.

Professional Experiences

Unity Developer, Kagura Games (2021-2023): Extract and integrate data from database and text files from Japanese Unity games to localize them in other languages. Alter and debug C# code to make sure the games work in other regions.

DevOps Developer, Ubisoft Montreal (2020-2021): Develop features of an automated build system, monitored it and assisted project members when failures arise.

IT Analyst, CGI (2020): Troubleshooted client's workers' technological issues and document the process on Service Now.

Unity Developer, Slipgames Corporation (2018-2020): Develop a mobile game using the Unity game engine. Tasks included coding game physics, UI, set up a database and integrating 3D assets.

Education

CDI College (2015-2017), Attestation of Collegial Studies, Programmer Analyst

Miscellaneous

• 4 years of Japanese classes